ieltsliz.com 2019-12-26

# Privacy Policy

Your privacy is very important to us. At ieltsliz.com, we have a few fundamental principles that we follow:

  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of our site.
  * We do use Google Analytics which includes tracking IP addresses for analysis purposes.

It is ieltsliz.com’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites.

 **Website Visitors**

Like most websites, ieltsliz.com collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. ieltsliz.com’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how ieltsliz’s visitors use its website. From time to time, ieltsliz.com may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

 **Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information**

Certain visitors to ieltsliz’s websites choose to interact with ieltsliz in ways that require ieltsliz to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that ieltsliz gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. See below:

 **Making comments  **

We ask visitors who comment on our blog to provide a username and email address. This information is stored by the website automatically to process your comment. Your IP address is also automatically stored when you leave a comment. Your email address is not available to the public, nor is your IP address. The name you use will be visible to the public.

  1. Your username can be any name or nickname. It does not need to be your full name or even your real name. Your username is the name you want the public to see.
  2. Your email address and IP address are NOT shown publicly.
  3. See this page to learn what is shown publicly and what is not shown to the public when you make a comment: [Recent IELTS Questions ](https://ieltsliz.com/recent-ielts-questions-and-topics/)

If you wish to have your comment and above details removed from this website , please email us: ieltsliz789@gmail.com. You will need to tell us the following information to delete your details and comment:

  1. username
  2. email
  3. date of comment
  4. page on which comment was posted
  5. general content of comment

 **Email Subscriptions**

Those who subscribed to receive ieltsliz.com updates and posts via email (via subscription), have submitted your email address. Those who subscribe do so to receive new posts, which may include IELTS  lesson discount offers, IELTS information and free lessons.

If you wish to unsubscribe in order to no longer receive these emails and to remove your email from this database, please follow the instructions for unsubscribing on this page: **[How to Unsubscribe](https://ieltsliz.com/unsubscribe/)**

 **Overall Gathering of Information**

ieltsliz collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with ieltsliz. ieltsliz.com does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

ieltsliz.com uses Google Analytics which does collect personal information such as your IP address. This is automatically collected by Google Analytics.

 **Aggregated Statistics**

ieltsliz.com may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its website. For instance, use spam screened by the Akismet service to help identify spam. ieltsliz.com may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, ieltsliz.com does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

 **Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information**

ieltsliz.com discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on ieltsliz.com’s behalf or to provide services available at ieltsliz’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using ieltsliz’s website, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. ieltsliz will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, ieltsliz.com discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when ieltsliz.com believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of ieltsliz.com, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an ieltsliz.com website and have supplied your email address, ieltsliz.com may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with ieltsliz.com and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. ieltsliz.com takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

 **Cookies**

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. ieltsliz.com uses cookies to help ieltsliz.com identify and track visitors, their usage of ieltsliz.com website, and their website access preferences.

ieltsliz.com visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using ieltsliz’s website, with the drawback that certain features of ieltsliz’s website may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

 **Google Analytics  **

ieltsliz.com uses Google Analytics. Google Analytics collects a lot of data from every visit / visitor to this website, but it does not store any personally identifiable information. A visitor’s IP address (which is now recognised as personal data by GDPR) is used to determine their physical location but the IP address itself is not data that can be accessed through Google Analytics. Information gathered by Google Analytics is used only be Google Analytis and ieltsliz.com.

** If you are not happy to accept this use of your information, you may wish to stop using ieltsliz.com **

 **Ads**

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by ieltsliz.com and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

 **Comments**

Comments and other content submitted to Akismet anti-spam service are not saved on our servers unless they were marked as false positives, in which case we store them long enough to use them to improve the service to avoid future false positives.

 **Privacy Policy Changes**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, ieltsliz.com may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in ieltsliz.com’s sole discretion. ieltsliz.com encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
